1) The net framework is
Software development platform developed by microsoft
To create applications which would run on the wwindow platform

2) The Net core framwoek is:
1,2,3,4,5,7
The latest web framework from Microsoft.
It is a cross platform.
It is free and open source and supported by Microsoft.
It can be used to develop web applications.
It is also compatible with .NET framework, Xamarin(for mobile application) via .NET standard library.
The latest version of .NET Core is .NET Core 3.0.
3) some differences between Net core and net framwork 
NET Core is the latest of .NET framework.
NET Core compatible with xamarin to develop mobile application. But .NET framework doesn’t have any tools to simplify mobile application.
4) Net Standard is
1 A set of APIs that all .NET platforms have to implement.
5)When should we use .netcore and  net standard class libarry project types
Use a .NET Standard library when you want to increase the number of apps that will be compatible with your library, and you are okay with a decrease in the .NET API surface area your library can access
Use a .NET Core library when you want to increase the .NET API surface area your library can access, and you are okay with allowing only .NET Core apps to be compatible with your library.
6)Can Asp.Net core work wwith the.net framework
yes
7.What is kestrel 
A cross-platform web server built for ASP.NET Core.
A default web server pick since it is used in all ASP.NET Core templates.

8 What is .csproj
The CSPROJ file type is primarily associated with Visual Studio .NET by Microsoft Corporation
9)Static files in ASP.net core are? Give Example 
+Static files, such as HTML, CSS, images, and JavaScript, are assets an ASP.NET Core app serves directly to clients. Some configuration is required to enable serving of these files.
+ Static files are stored in the project root directory. The default directory is <content_root> / wwwroot, but it can be changed via the UseWebRoot method. See Original and Original Web Content for more information.
+Static files are accessible via a path relative to the web root.wwwroot
css
images
js
+Set HTTP response headers
+Static file authorization
+Enable directory browsing
10) Startup.cs files is to.
+ASP.NET Core apps use a Startup class, which is named Startup by convention. 
The Startup class:
Optionally includes a ConfigureServices method to configure the app's services. A service is a reusable component that provides app functionality. Services are configured—also described as registered—in ConfigureServices and consumed across the app via dependency injection (DI) or ApplicationServices.
Includes a Configure method to create the app's request processing pipeline.
+The Startup class is specified to the app when the app's host is built. The app's host is built when Build is called on the host builder in the Program class. The Startup class is usually specified by calling the WebHostBuilderExtensions.UseStartup<TStartup> method on the host builder:

11) how many common methods in starup.cs file? List and Purpose of each
The ConfigureServices method:he typical pattern is to call all the Add{Service} methods and then call all of the services.Configure{Service} methods
+The Configure method:The Configure method is used to specify how the app responds to HTTP requests. The request pipeline is configured by adding middleware components to an IApplicationBuilder instance. IApplicationBuilder is available to the Configure method, but it isn't registered in the service container. Hosting creates an IApplicationBuilder and passes it directly to Configure.
Convenience methods:o configure services and the request processing pipeline without using a Startup class, call ConfigureServices and Configure convenience methods on the host builder. Multiple calls to ConfigureServices append to one another. If multiple Configure method calls exist, the last Configure call is used.
12) Dependency injection DI is to?
DI is a type of Inversion of Control (IoC)

Inversion of Control is just a concept for a group of design principles aimed at eliminating dependencies in code. It works by automatically creating instances of dependencies in other modules and putting in a place called a container.

A simple container is a factory that is responsible for providing instances of the requested type.

DI is a special type of IoC that allows dependencies (other components, services in the program) to be injected (directly) from the container into a constructor (constructor function) or a public property. (public properties) of a class depending on them.
